Ionut Moraru

in linkedin.com/in/morion

+40 723 047 423

https://www.morion4000.com

Summary

Seasoned software developer with over ten years of experience in full-stack web development and systems architecture. My experience has provided me with the innovative and technical skills necessary to successfully provide multifaceted technical solutions across a wide range of software platforms.

I am currently interested in Blockchain technologies, smart contracts, automation, and IT infrastructure, and got certified in Solidity development by Consensys. I have experience working with the Ethereum and the Web3 stack, as well as contributing to open source projects.

Experience



Founder / Full Stack Developer

May 2018- Present

Hostero

Managing the whole operation, and using this opportunity to develop my soft-skills as well as develop a product from scratch.

- Developing and managing the infrastructure for running the software
- Building the various components of the system (website, dashboard, API, workers, containers)
- Social media and marketing strategies
- · Community management

Tech stack: Node.js, AngularJS, React.js, Typescript, MySQL, Docker, Rancher, REST, Ubuntu.



Full Stack / Blockchain Developer

Apr 2014 - Jan 2020

Eloquentix

5 years 10 months

Worked closely with clients, and helped them develop products in various stages. I have worked on projects from zero (MVP, POC), and also production-ready, large scale ones.

My experience ranges from working with Fintech companies, as well as companies from the energy monitoring and management industry.

Tech stack: Node.js, AngularJS, Solidity, Python, MySQL, Cassandra, Apache Mesos, Docker, Rancher, REST, Ubuntu, Ethereum.



Automation Specialist

Sep 2018 - Dec 2019

WebDollar

1 year 4 months

Worked on implementing open-source tools and services tailored to the community.

- Built a dashboard for monitoring full nodes
- Automated the deployment and management of the network for testing (Testnet)
- Built the bounty system

- Built a Telegram tipping bot
- Contributed to the core project

The complete list with tools developed: https://www.hostero.eu/tools

Tech stack: Node.js, MySQL, Docker, Rancher, REST, Ubuntu, Blockchain.



Back-end Developer

Mar 2013 - Jun 2013

SimplySocial, a Matchfire Co. company

4 months

Implemented highly scalable and available applications for crawling and aggregating social media accounts.

Tech stack: Python, RabbitMQ, MySQL, REST, Ubuntu.



New Media / Full Stack Developer

Sep 2011 - May 2012

MMT Digital

9 months

Created and maintained microsites on Microsoft Sharepoint. Later switched to building educational platforms.

Tech stack: PHP, MySQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Microsoft Sharepoint.



Co-Founder / Mobile Developer

Nov 2010 - May 2012

Codeboxed 1 year 7 months

Worked on creating mobile applications for various clients, and was a contributor to the Appcelerator Titanium community and one of the first certified developers.

Tech stack: PHP, Javascript, MySQL, Objective-C, Cocoa Touch, Titanium.



Full Stack / Mobile Developer

Apr 2009 - May 2011

2 years 2 months Eloquentix

Developed web applications using technologies such as PHP, Javascript, and MySQL. Later switched to developing native iPhone applications.

Tech stack: PHP, Javascript, MySQL, Objective-C, Cocoa Touch.

Education



West University of Timisoara

2008 - 2011

Computer Science

Skills



JavaScript • Node.js • Python • SQL • AngularJS • Microservices • Docker • Solidity • React.js • **TypeScript**

Certifications

ConsenSys Academy Online Developer Program 2018 • ConsenSys Academy

2018 - Present